SHAILASHREE K.N.

#206, Eco-Nana Apartment, 4th Cross Manjunatha Layout, RT Nagar, Bangalore-560032

Mobile: (+91)7760969222 /9980284859; Email: spshailashree@gmail.com

REVIEW

Experienced Kannada teacher with passion for both written words and teaching, uses this passion to connect students to the material. Possesses good presentation and communication skills that ensure students learn the material presented as well as they can.

OBJECTIVES

- To obtain a position as Kannada lecturer in which strong dedication to the total development of students and a high degree of enthusiasm can be fully utilized.
- Certified Kannada teacher with 19 years of experience in teaching, looking for a Kannada lecturing position. I am motivated to work with students and fully utilize my communication and teaching skills using the latest technology.

KEY SKILLS AND CORE COMPETENCIES

- Good communicator Mature, patient, responsible and positive attitude.
- Approachable Good listening skills.
- Passionate and energetic.
- Planning and organizational skills using Microsoft Excel.
- Technological learning through Microsoft Teams, Power point Presentations & Google Meets.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

B.Ed (Special Education Learning Disability)

[2011-2012]

Obtained B.Ed (Special Education Learning Disability) in the year 2011-2012 from KSOU, Mysore in Kannada.

M.A (Kannada) [2003]

Obtained MA in the year 2003 from KSOU, Mysore in Kannada.

B.Sc CBZ [1995]

Obtained Bsc CBZ in 1995 from Maharani College, Mysore in Science.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SMT. KAMALABHAI EDUCATION INSTITUTION (SKEI) (CBSE)

[2020-Present]

Presently working as Kannada teacher at Smt. Kamalabhai Education Institution (CBSE), Queens Road, Bangalore

SIDDHARTHA SCHOOL (CBSE)

[2014-2020]

Worked as Kannada teacher at Siddartha School (CBSE), RT Nagar, Bangalore.

PRASIDDHI SCHOOL (ICSE)

[2005-2011]

Worked as Kannada teacher at Prasiddhi School (ICSE), Palace Grounds, Bangalore.

FLORENCE ENGLISH SCHOOL (STATE BOARD)

[2001-2005]

Worked as Kannada High School teacher at Florence English School, Vasanthnagar, Bangalore.

KEY FUNCTIONS

- Developed methodology for online-learning using technology during COVID-19 pandemic which has helped students to learn from home.
- Developed Kannada lesson plans in line with the national curriculum: Planned Kannada lessons to meet curriculum standards for hybrid learning (Online & Offline).
- Helped students understand, speak, read and write in Kannada using technology.
- Delivered engaging, coherent lectures and motivating lessons to students across all Key Stages. Utilized learning technology in the planning and delivery of lessons.
- Modified assignments and activities to meet the learning needs of individual students – Identified and sorted into small, similarly skilled groups.
- Classroom management: Prepared Kannada classroom and coursework materials, homework assignments, and handouts. Prepared course work, planned class sessions: Selected/integrated appropriate instructional materials for classroom instruction – Organized/delivered classroom teaching to students. Arranged extracurricular activities and set targets for pupils.
- Evaluated the students' class work and assignments: Graded tests, essays, reports
 and other assignments online/offline

 Regularly provided students with feedback in
 line with the faculty assessment systems.
- Maintained weekly/Monthly/Quarterly progess of students to achieve excellence using Microsoft Excel.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Produced high quality resources and took part in the creation of new schemes of work using technology for hybrid adaptation (Online & Offline learning).
- Communicated with parents, students and the teaching administration Met with students, parents and other educators on a constant basis to discuss student progress.
- Maintained discipline in the classroom Created a vibrant teaching atmosphere.
 Recorded and maintained accurate student attendance records and grades. Worked in accordance with school behavior policy to set high standards and expectations for students.
- Tracked progress through assessment and reporting within own teaching groups.
 Monitored the progression of students in teaching groups using Microsoft Excel.
- Took part in the school quality assurance Attended and contributed to school meetings and weekly briefing – Worked as a team supporting school teachers in spreading and sharing good practices.
- Interrogated other instructors and interpreted relevant data to use as achievement tools.
- Engaged in the self-review processes together with the school management.
- Identified students at risk of underachievement and ensured that appropriate interventions were in place using weekly monitoring systems.

DECLARATION

I hereby declared that all the above said information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge, belief and information.

Place: Bangalore Yours Sincerely, Date: 14.01.2023

(Shailashree K.N)